Heat.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Nat.
[music] Hey. Hey.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hi everyone, good evening. Thank you so
much for joining us today and welcome to
the workshop on agentic AI from design
to deployment under Google cloud geni
academy powered by actskll. My name is
Manita Huja and I'm your host for the
day. So
moving forward uh let's welcome Mr.
Tuya. He is a developer relations
engineer at Google with seven plus years
of experience in designing, developing,
testing and maintaining software
solutions for various domains and
industries. Welcome Mr. Tuya. How are
you?
>> Thank you Manage. I'm feeling great. So
yeah, I'm Tuya. Good to see everyone. Uh
thank you so much for tuning in. So this
workshop is actually the part of
expanded ape edition from Google cloud
geni academy 2026. This is a premier
challengebased learning program designed
to significantly upscale the technical
professional and developer across the
region in genai technologies on Google
cloud. Right? So there are a few tracks
to it and the academy is con instructed
into like three different tracks. Right?
So for today our workshop is focused
specifically on the first track which is
build and deploy AI agent using Gemini
ADK and cloud run. Right. So the next
part is the track one is actually
focuses on enabling developer to design
build and deploy agentic AI application
using Gemini and the agent development
kit or ADK. The track emphasis running
AI agent as scalable production ready
services on cloud run and you will be
learning fundamental of agents
deployment and how to run these agents
as manage serverless services right be
it one single agent or cloud run or
multiple agents working together right
so clearly define the task and it's all
called you know from the HTTP or like
API endpoints and this is all covered in
the hands code lab that we were going to
go through later right so this is kind
teaches you how to move from just
building a prototype into a production
ready agent and I hope we are ready for
it right so AI agents why are we
covering that right so AI agents are the
next frontier in technologies nowadays
like everyone is trying to build AI
agents and having to learn how to play
AI agent for your own need is very
important right so the first thing let
me cover a little bit on how the
technology has evolved into AI agents
started from just large language model
with prom, right? So a few years ago, we
started having large language model,
right? And you probably using it to do
some other things like you know creating
uh report or maybe like asking specific
questions and maybe even like analyzing
specific trends and so on. But after
some time you start to realize that the
last language model actually provide a
very maybe plausible answer sometime but
not very accurate. So you want to
actually make those uh large language
model produce a correct output or maybe
what we call grounding right? So you
want to ground the results with the
correct answer. So you kind of want to
put that as like a retrieval augmented
generation RA. So, RG actually helped
you to identify what are the similar you
know maybe even for like correct
responses that you should actually take
into it into context before sending out
the answer. So, hallucination reduced by
having this kind of ground truth
probably together with the large
language model into the context window
so that the the large models are just
you know not just sprouting nonsense
it's actually grounded to the truth.
That's why we call it grounding. Right?
So after we have been able to ground
those model, what we are lacking off is
to do tasks for us. Right? So be it you
know extracting information from the
latest API or retrieving information
from the database itself. Right? So the
agents at the time were not very capable
of retrieving things by themselves. So
we started having this thing called
extension or toolings where you start to
call this actionable things like maybe
retrieve example from a database or
maybe go and like read information from
this file or even to do something like
uh you know invoking the API or you know
calling some other agents to do some
other things as well. Right? So I just
introduced a term called agent but that
is what happened after we have tools
enabled into our large language model.
Right? So once you have many tools with
blood language model and the retrieval
step you can form this small unit that
is called agent and agent has like many
tools and also reasonable uh you know
reasoning loop that can help to
reasoning whether I can use these tools
to complete certain tasks or not. So
once we have this particular information
and you know the the through the RAG and
also the actionable things from the tool
links you can have many agents that can
do different task right maybe one agent
to book calendar one agent to make
appointment right one agent to make a
phone call one agent to one agent to
extract the relevant information and so
on. This is where we started having this
thing called multi- aent system right.
So multi- aent system are those kind of
unit that works together and that
actually you know in a collaborative
manner to achieve certain common task
that they are supposed to be doing
right. So this is where we are right now
we're trying to build multi- aent system
that can technically you know work
together retrieve example you know get
the relevant information execute actions
and so on on behalf of you. So go deeper
into you know AI agent formation or
formula is that AI agent has three
particular uh component right the first
component that we have is a model it
could be Gemini model Gemma model right
2.5 flash 3.0 pro 3.0 zero flash uh
gemma 3 and so on right and it could be
powered by you know any of the model
that is capable of reasoning and so on
then you have toolings which enable you
to assess know API databases and even
delegate some of the agents uh to do the
things that you need to do right so once
you have those tools and the model what
you are needing is pretty much just to
uh give them persona you know like
instruction gut rails having some memory
of what are the things that to be done
what the what are the things that you
know uh we did already right so some
memory for the agents to keep track of
stuff so this is where the orchestration
piece comes in right orchestration kind
of like bring those large language
models and the tool all together and
then you know it have like one
consolidated place to have like uh a
ways to have instruction and also like
some description and also some memories
and even being able to keep track of the
task that you do and you haven't done
yet, right? So, this is like AI agent in
a nutshell, right? So, going deeper into
AI agent, right? The ADK is pretty much
just to help with that orchestration
piece and like you know create AI agent
in a very simple manner. So, what is
ADK? ADK stand for agent development
kit. It's a flexible and also a modular
and it's importantly it's open source
right is open source framework that
helps to develop and deploy AI agent is
optimized for Gemini model but it's
still models and deployment agnostic so
you could use any of the model as long
as it's supported by light LLM library
you can use it with the ADK and then you
could also make sure to you know
seamless compatibility with any of the
any other platform that you want to
deploy it
You can see from here that agent ADK has
like agents you know birectional
streaming even for evaluation if you
want to uh kind of test the output you
can also do things like call back
planning and orchestration and so on
right so if you want to also store
artifacts you also have the artifact
management and if you want to execute
code to get certain you know output out
we also have a code execution tool that
you can use to support it right so this
is like overview of what AD DDK can do
and we will go deeper into what it can
do and uh you know how does it actually
works in in using it to let's say deploy
it into cloud run. So I mentioned about
cloud run right. So before I go deeper
into what cloud run is and what Google
cloud is I want to go deeper a little
bit on some of the topic that we have
we're going to cover in lab right. So
one is agents in ADK. So there are three
distinct type of agents that is
available to build in ADK. One is the
large language model based agent. This
is straightforward right? So you have
large language motor as a brain acting
on for the agent and whenever the user
inputs something the input will then go
into the agent and agent will then use a
large language as a processing unit then
give you the output from the model as
the output right so pretty much doing
things like two calling you know doing
things like deleation those can be done
from the large language model based
agent part sometimes right you don't
really need large language model to do
certain things maybe you wants something
you know some other agents to help to
manage those large model right maybe you
are trying to orchestrate them uh make
them runs in serals so that you the
agents run one after another or you just
want to make them run all in parallel so
that they are more sufficient or they
are more efficient in running things
right so this is where the workflow
agents comes in workflow agents help to
manage the workflow so that you can
pretty much control the way agents are
going to exit execute either one after
another are they either in the loop or
in parallel right but sometimes your use
cases are very niche so you might need
to create custom agent so custom agent
actually allow you to implement uh
operation that is unique to your
business logic and you can control the
flow as you wish and also there's some
other specialized control right and you
cannot basically build those things by
using let's say workflow agent that
exists right maybe some some other you
know fuzzy logic kind of uh agents that
you want to create you can use the
custom agents to do that okay so so
these are going deeper into the workflow
agent right so why I'm covering this is
we were actually making use of some of
the workflow agent in the lab and there
are three different type that I cover in
a workflow engine one is a sequential
one so the sequential one actually like
you can see from the image is go one two
and three right everything goes in order
right and it doesn't really jump it
doesn't really you know um go to one or
three or something like that, right? So
this is sequential, right? It will make
sure that the agents run in parallel uh
sequential by itself. The next one is
parallel. So parallel more like you have
started from zero and then that zero can
actually spin up into one, two and three
at the same time, right? So they're
actually using that to actually maybe
you know speed up, right? Maybe you're
doing a research work and you want to
research into many different sources
once you can do that, right? This is to
execute multiple sub aents in parallel.
But sometimes maybe you are doing like a
coding test or reviewing the report and
stuff like that. So this is where you
will need to do some looping. So looping
actually is to ensure or maybe even like
some of the tasks are too difficult. So
you want to like check it out and you
know make sure that you are repeating
the same step to improve further and
further and further. Right? So either
refinement or correcting mistakes. One
example could be you are creating a
coding agent. that coding agents will
have to pass 10 test cases, right? The
so first pass they just generated like
one, two and three start with like you
know creating the function, you know,
fighting the decorators and all that
like formatting it blah blah blah and
then after three is actually only passes
seven test cases. You need to pass the
other three, right? So then you have to
go back to the step one to start
generating the code or modifying the
code in a ways that it passes the other
three remaining test cases. Right? So
this is actually a loop use case and of
course the loop will execute until uh
two condition. One is when your
condition is met in this case all the 10
cases all the 10 test cases have passes
or the maximum number of loop that you
allow maybe you put as five. So it will
run up to five times before it stop or
uh is condition is met which is uh
passing all 10 test cases. I hope that
kind of explain uh the overview of what
agents are, what's ADK, what kind of
agents that you have in the ADK and also
what are the workflow agents that you
can make use to create like a different
type of uh agents. Right now go deeper
down into what is cloud run because this
lab going to make use of cloud run to be
able to uh deploy things and making sure
that the things that you are you're
building can be accessed by all
different people and not just yourself
on your local laptop. Right? So usually
when you build agent like this, the
agents will be then accessible only to
you and once you have you know built it
and you want to like how do I make it
accessible to my friends, my family, my
my you know my classmates and so on is
very hard right so ADK actually make it
very easy for you to deploy uh using
using the the ADK deploy command which
we will go through in the lab in a bit
right so why do we need to use cloud run
is cloud run is from Google cloud a
service that is serverless so that you
don't have to worry so much about how
much to procure, right? You just have to
send it and most of the things are being
taken care of because it's a fully
managed service platform, right? So
serless platform means you're not taking
care of the infrastructure and
everything. Google cloud is taking care
of it. All you need to do is just put
your Docker image or something. Then you
just upload it and should be okay,
right? The next thing, right? So a lot
of people talk about, you know, scaling,
right? Can I scale it up to x number of
uh computer or can I stay up to zero if
I'm not using it. So cloud run actually
support scale to zero functionality. So
whenever you uh there's nobody using it
the agent's not using it right and and
it's cannot actually go down into zero
so that you're not actually costing any
more additional cost if nobody using the
agent right so that's something that you
can consider to do because that's what
cloud runs offer. So what is cloud run
is covered right then why do we need to
develop the cloud run is that when you
let's say create an agent and you want
to make it production you have to make
sure that the agents are available all
the time right like there's no point
your agents only available from like you
know 2 to 5 or something right you have
to make sure everything is available
because people might be accessing from
different time zone right different time
different free time that they have so
the availability have to go out so cloud
run actually provide right it's
serverless it's managed and is actually
give you the loggings and access control
and
Right. So this is where is the power of
you know deploying things on cloud run
because it actually give you
availability and of course I mentioned
about the scale down to zero not just
going down to zero if you need the scale
to like maybe scale down to like 10 20
100 you can actually scale automatically
using cloud run as well. So you just
have to put the maximum number of uh
upscaling that you want and then it will
actually scale up to that maximum number
that you defined. Right. So the last
point is being you know this is Google
cloud right. So cloud run actually have
like uh some of the networks in in terms
of the internet because everything is
all connected in Google cloud right. So
you get access to databases, you can
access to some of the services we have
for cloud run uh Google cloud and
actually you know things like Gemini
APIs because they are all in cloud you
actually have a latency uh smaller than
you know maybe you're using it from your
local laptop right because that is
inside the same ecosystem so it's
actually easier for them to access to
each other
right so this is the hands-on lab right
we're going to start uh doing some
implementation and deployment of AI
agent right we were going through in
terms of like creating a zoo agent. So
it will use Wikipedia to extract all the
information. Whenever you ask something
about like animals right zoo right you
know like monkey tigers and so on it
will actually go extract information
from Wikipedia and then give you a
better answer. So we're not going to
just you know use it at loco we're
actually going to be deploying this on
cloud run and then access that cloud run
server directly from our terminal as
well. So if you wants to uh go code this
one out, you can actually scan the QR
code here or use the link to access the
collab. I will actually run through the
collab in a bit. Right. So once you have
Okay. Uh what will be happen is you will
receive some instruction with the email
to redeem uh the cloud credit that is
required to complete this lab. Right? If
you do not receive it, uh make sure you
know you reach out to the teams and also
check out these commands uh from this
particular session. There might be some
links that you can actually use to
redeem that as well. You may have
redemption links and also some
instruction for you to start claiming
the Google cloud credit required to run
this lab. Right? What I will do is I
will actually start from you know
explaining the code lab and then going
deeper into doing the hands-on lab by
maybe creating the Google cloud projects
and al also at the same time deploying
the AI agent to cloud run. So yeah,
let's head into the Google cloud lab
hands on. Okay, so this lab is uh with
build and deploy AI agent lab on cloud
runs, right? So what we're going to do
is we're going to actually start
creating some of the agents. Uh it's
very cute with the zoo and you know the
the deployment part. We're going to use
the agents to like link up to Wikipedia.
At the same time, we will actually run
the cloud run, right? So what I'm going
to do is you can actually read why
deploy to cloud run. I kind of cover it
from the slide just now but what we need
to do now is to create a project. So the
project setup right you will receive and
like I repeat again you will rece you
will receive an instruction and at the
same time the links to redeem it and
then once you redeem and create the uh
you know projects you should be able to
follow along with this lab and uh for
the sake of you know creating it I will
actually help you to show you how to
actually create the project right we're
going to get so let's say the first
thing is you have to go to cloud right
so cloud is console.cloud.google.com
google.com. So once you go to
console.cloud google.com you will be
seeing like this right? So this is where
the the you will see this is I have the
project already but what I need to do is
I need to create this um project right.
So what I would do I would say create
the project. So create a project is
actually over here. If you click this
sometimes you don't see anything here
because you don't have any informations
or any project before right because I
already have the project I'm seeing it
over here but if you don't have it no
worry just click on it then you will see
this particular things called new
project right. So click on this new
project and then you will see right once
you claim the trial billing account that
we sent to you, you'll be seeing the
billing account over here. If you don't
see it, it's okay. What you need to do
is just name it, right? I'm going to
just name it AI agent zoo, right, for
this particular one. And remember this
is the project name and there's some
project ID and so on. But these two
sometimes the same, sometime not the
same just to be mindful, right? So
project name and project ID sometimes
same sometimes not same right so I
already name it I have the billing
account I'm going to just click on
creation right location just leave it no
location uh no organization is fine
right so once you clicked it what it's
going to do is it will just start
creating a project right give it like
good 30 seconds it will start and you
click this button select project so once
you click select project right you
should be able to see the AI agent zoom
okay so AI agent zoo if it's showing
here then you are good right so the next
step what do we need to do for the next
step the next step it says that need to
open the cloud shell editor right so
cloud shell editor there are a few ways
to open it my favorite one is to just go
to shell
share.cloudg cloud.google.com. So shadow
part ofgoogle.com is cloudshell uh
editor thing. Right? So what we need to
do is I will actually close all the
things that I opened up previously.
Right? This is where I actually show you
all these things are doing. Right? Let
me just clear this out.
Okay. So the first step that you need to
do is to authorize. So if there's a
popup that coming to you, you need to
authorize it. And then if there's like
uh all this thing you want to see you
know terminal you don't see it you click
in terminal and all that right the first
step we need to do is to enable the API
so this is so that you can actually
access some of the resources from Google
cloud run right so if you click on it
you can actually copy this so this
Google cloud service enable you know
Google cloud run artifact registry cloud
build AI platform which is vertex AI and
then compute right so these are Google
API that you can enable all you need to
Copy this, right? And then you paste it
over here. Okay. So, here's one thing to
know, right? If you do not see this
yellow color thing, right? So, this is
very important, right? This yellow color
thing, if you don't see it, you can do
the step that mentioned over here. This
one waiting developer, right? So, there
this step that you need to do which is
here.
Google cloud config set project then
your project ID remember project ID is
not the same not always the same as
project name you need to make sure you
get that project ID from the portal
itself right so let's go and enable this
API so I'm going to just copy and then
paste it down here right so if you paste
it down here wait I'm copying the wrong
one let me actually copy back the first
one
which is here copy it Right? So you copy
it, you enable it. Right? Then what it's
going to do, it's going to start
enabling at the back end. Right? So it
might take some times. Then you can see
operation is successfully. Then you're
done. Right? If for some reason it
taking a little bit longer, it's okay.
Right? If it's too long, right? Maybe 5
minutes, 10 minutes, ah, then you need
to restart the whole session, right? You
restart simple just come here, refresh
it, then it's gone, right? So you will
just like reprovision it blah blah blah.
you will connect back to the same one.
So don't worry if there's like oh I I I
don't know what happened right you can
you can repeat one more time as well you
just repeat it it's enabled already it's
not going to disable it's going to
enable then it's enable again you just
wait right so it actually taking me some
time it's say okay see finish right so
don't worry so much if the the
instructions is like taking too long
just refresh and then re rerun it right
it should be able to run it by itself
okay so next step what we need to do
right we need actually so this actually
explain what particular API does go and
read it out that yourself. The next step
is to develop uh creating the
environment right. So you can just like
create this. So this is to create right.
So cd go back to the main home directory
make directory create the make directory
right and then go into the directory.
Once you have it Google cloud shell open
workspace the folder name. So the folder
name actually open up this folder.
Right. So let me actually show that.
Copy then paste it in. So once you paste
it in it will actually open up this
Google cloud zoo agent right so zoo
guide agent the folder will be then open
it over here right if you don't open
what do you do refresh type it in should
be able to open right so once it's open
I'm going to skip this because I already
done it right and then what you need to
do is to create the requirement text if
you click this it will actually open up
the requirement txt let me show you it
will actually pop up here right so then
you just have to copy the content. So
I'm going to close this one because I
don't need it. Going to put here, right?
Copy this. So we are using Google ADK
1.14. So this version if you want to,
you can update to the latest one. If you
don't want to, just continue whatever
you have. We're going to install Google
ADK, LC chain, Wikipedia, and so on.
Then we're going to create the virtual
environment, source the environment,
then we install the requirement. Right?
So we install this already. Just execute
that your command. It should be good.
Then the next step that we need to do is
to set the environment. Right? So
remember I told you the project ID is
slightly different. So they trying to
get a project ID from the command line.
And then you're going to get a project
number as well. This is important for
deploying the the cloud run. Right? So
and then you're going to have this
service account. Why are we using
service account is we definitely don't
want the agent to have all the
permission that we have as a user,
right? So we want to make sure that the
agent only have access to the things
that agent needs, right? not based on
what we have. So that's why we need to
create this service account. So once you
have the service account name, you can
actually put it in right. So it will
actually put this something like this.
Let's say I'm copy this, right? And just
paste it here. I hope that is easy to
see. Let me just drag it up right. So
you can see from here, right? Let me
clear it up. Paste it out here. What
it's going to do is it's actually going
to like assign those project ID and blah
blah blah into your terminal. Right?
So once you have it you need to create
the environment. The environment
actually have the project ID, service
number, service account name, service
account. So service account follow a
specific type of uh like the Gmail
address like that, right? You have the
service account name, project ID and
then imgservice.com,
right? And for the model we using 2.5
flash. You want to try 3.0, go ahead,
right? 3.3 3 pro preview three flash
preview 3 pro three flash whichever
works for you just go and try it right
so by typing this up you're going to
create the environment file so let me
show you what dot environment file looks
like this is what it looks like right
and do not upload the environment file
to like GitHub profile or something
right environment is supposed to be
secret so don't upload them uh this is
like very important things that we
should talk to everyone right do not
upload the environment file even if is
is it safe right so in this one
technically safe because you're not
actually exposing most of like maybe
project number is relatively sensitive
but you you're not actually making some
damage right but if you have like API
key ah this is the problem if you have
API key do not ever upload the do
environment to the GitHub or something
like that right so make sure those are
secret and then save it in your
particular location
so the next step what we're going to do
right so it go straightforward uh start
creating the agent workflow already you
need to start creating this thing called
India py so once you have in py because
adk runs as like a python package. So
then you need this initializer. So why
is initializer right? Initializer very
simple just from here just import the
agent object that's it right this that's
all you need and then you have this
agent file agent file starting to have
like couple of code right so you import
agent you import sequential agent that
we cover remember you have the two
context and also using land chain tools.
So ADK actually works with like lchain
or crew AI tools. So those are like
third party tools that you can use
together with the ADK. So you don't have
to then you know use a specific tools
with that a specific uh framework ADK
actually works with those stuff. Right.
Right. Right. So because we are using
Wikipedia you can kind of see that
there's a land chain tool that you're
using Wikipedia over here. Once you use
the Wikipedia you can see there's
actually authentication and all sort of
like you know ID tokens to help you to
authenticate. We are going to set up the
cloud logging as well. So cloud logging
is where you keep track of all the stats
that happening in your your application
and we will actually load the
environment over there. Then we have
this model right this model could be
whatever that you set from the uh
environment that you set over previous
time right envir. So once we have it
we're going to have this thing called uh
add prompt to state. So this is actually
how to save the prompt into a specific
logging right. So you can see it has the
two context and it say try to prompt it.
So once you have the prompt you're going
to go to lock it into the lock. So log
is like you know the logging that we
initialized previously over here right
kind of lock it and then what we need to
also do is to run those uh Wikipedia
tools right? So we just configuring the
tools over here. So this is just a
function we're going to use it in our
agent in a bit right. We not using it
yet. We're just defining them. So you
can kind of read into like wait what are
the things that is going on or why do we
initialize this particular functions and
so on you can read it over here and then
once we have those tools first we need
to initialize the researcher agent right
so researcher agent is straightforward
is just research things you can see the
instruction here is a primary re
researcher that can access both internal
zoo data and then external knowledge
from the wikipedia right so the the
thing is set up in the ways that it will
use the large language model knowledge
first then if you kind of don't know or
maybe not very sure then you use the
Wikipedia right so something like a
grounding happening over here you can
see you have access to two tools one
tool is to figure out the uh animal
right specific data about the animal at
the zoo right name ages location right
that's one tools right the other two is
for searching Wikipedia right so like
find whatever there is information that
available first then if not then use a
Wikipedia to find right and you You have
to synthesize the result from the tools
that you use and then the primary data
output. That's that's pretty much it,
right? So from here tools you attach the
wikipa tools and then the output key
here is research data. So why do we need
to define output key is this output key
will be assigned as a key pair value
when you pass into the next agent. So if
you have like output key defined in this
particular agent that agent will have
the output from this agent will have the
output key or research data then you can
call that research data directly from
over here like this you see the research
data right so what's happening is this
comprehensive researcher will research
and then the passing on to the respond
formatter so respond formatter will then
use that research data using the
keywords right the output key then so
instead of like you know passing on the
entire context over here it just pass in
that key then it will go and read from
the contact itself right this is a
respond for matter agent and then once
we have this two right the next one is
the tour guide right so the to guide
workflow is what you're going to do is
whenever user ask something it will go
and research first once you have all the
data already make sure to format the
final response so this is what it is
right so the sequential agent
remember run one after another. So
whenever user type in something it will
actually run the comprehensive
researcher part and then it will pass it
on to the respond formatter that respond
formatter will then give give the output
with like a very good format right so
like predefined format right maybe good
or not is up to the individual but it's
predefined format it will actually
respond back in the format so of course
once we have all these agents defined
all the tools defined you know all the
function defined you need a start point
right the start point is what we call
root agent so root agent is the agent
that have helped to greet or like you
know hey here's what are the things that
I can do and then delegate uh whenever
you know user ask question into the tour
guide workflow you see so this agent is
named greeter so this is like a main
entry for the zoo tour guide instruction
is just to like let user help them about
the animal we have in the zoo whenever
user respond to like app prompt state or
blah blah blah blah and then you can
kind of use this uh you know tools that
it has so app prompt to
is the uh prompt state and then if uh
after using the tool transfer the
control into the tour guide right so why
it say transfer control because you are
using sub agent so there's another ways
to use agent like agent as a tools or
like just include that together with the
agents the two as well but in this
particular case we are using something
called transfer control that's why we're
using a sub agent right whenever the
user coming in talk to the root agent if
they're asking about the question the
root agents want to transfer control uh
to the sub agent so the sub aent can do
their job right so there's something
like that right so you got to figure out
whether you want to like transfer
control or you want to take control just
want to get the output and so on right
so this why you have to decide as a
agent designer to design what is good
what's not good whether that fits my
particular use case or not so once you
have all this thing you can read out
online uh what's exactly going on but
this is the full agent of py right so it
actually have everything all the import
statements
all the logging and also all the prompt
that you want to save all the
configuration research agent and so on
right all you need to do here I mean you
can of course see everything is like uh
correct and all that right you just have
to like copy this copy this then you
come to cloud shell right there's agent
py right I'm just going to just like
paste it in right so you see my agent py
I'm going to go down a little bit let me
just screw down
Scroll down. Yep. Nope. It's hard.
Okay. So, never mind. So, you can kind
of see like from here, right? You can
see that all the for all the code have
been copied into my agent. Py, right?
So, you can you can like go down. Let me
see. Yeah, see. Okay. So, you can kind
of see all the codes are here, right?
But now I cannot see my terminal. Never
mind. Just move it up. You can kind of
see the terminal now. Okay. Okay, the
next step that we need to do is to um
prepare the application, right? So you
can kind of see from the the here that
you know all the file that you need,
right? So we have the uh init file,
environment file, agent file,
requirement.txt, make sure you have all
the file, right? Init environment agent
requirement. Once you have all the files
like this, we can then you know solve
the env. So that means that we are
actually loading that environment file
that we just created into our own our
own terminal section. I can copy this
paste it here. Right? So once you paste
it here
then you will have this like so remember
we are actually going to use service
account. We're not going to use our own
credential to run the agent. We're going
to create a service account. You just
copy this and create it. I actually
created it already but let's see if it
is give me error by creating another
one. So let me just create it. It going
to take like maybe like good one or two
minute. You see it's already been
created. So you can see that it's
already there right? So once you have
the service account what we need to do
is to grant the Vertex AI user row.
Remember we just want to use the user
and we just want to provide the
necessary access to our service account.
We don't want to provide any random
access to our service account. Right? We
have to control in a way right because
we this is like a production system
right? Make sure that every single
assess that you have as a service
account is valid. Right? So we need to
go and just do this. Grant all this
assess it will take like you know less
than one minute to to get it done again.
If it's like something going on stucking
you know the connection loss refresh it
run again should be fine. I will run
again. Like you can see uh let me show
you. So it's already successful but you
know if if it does something like I
don't know disconnected refresh it right
it will just refresh like provisioning
connecting once it connected I can just
uh run again so once you run again it it
will do the same thing so there's like
no impact right see it it runs
everything so that's the beauty of it
right so most of the command here are
actually rerunnable even if you rerun it
nothing going to change right so if you
are not very sure hey did I run it ready
or if there's some error going on just
rerun it. It's fine, right? If you got
any any error just uh you know reach out
to the people from the commands and then
you know or you reach out to me directly
is fine as well. Right? So the next step
is deploying. So once you deploy here is
that you we are using the u uvx command
so from Google ADK to deploy it. So
deploying like ADK deploy cloud run the
projects the projects the project ID the
region you can choose the region that
you close to use and then the service
name is what the service name of your
cloud uh the agent going to be here we
call it zoo tour guide right and then
with UI so that actually you know spin
out the UI as well and then you have the
label on like what are the labels that
you need and then you can like have the
service account so service account we
just created we attach it here okay so
what I need to do just copy this thing
then I'm going to run it across here. So
once it start running right what's going
to happen it will just spinning off you
know like sending the code you can see
all this like source code file and
everything generated and all this right
so your code actually compact then send
to the cloud and cloud spin up some of
the container right some artificial uh
some artifacts repository get uploaded
and stuff like that it actually go
through step by step over here right you
get prompted like hey this actually
require you to create a artifact
registry docker right remember cloud run
work with docker so you need to actually
create this artifact registry to store
[clears throat] the local repository
right so just say yes I will create it
type yes enter if there's like uh
authenticated version because this one
we just testing right in production
system what we need to do is to make
sure we have like virtual private
network and like proper authentication
to access the agent right maybe you want
to have some agents that is free to
access to any of the customer maybe some
premium services or premium agent or
things that can do a little bit more uh
you know maybe like registering or like
you know, booking the tour or like
buying the ticket. You might want to
have access to some specific privilege
information and all that. You might want
to have like a firewall or some kind of
like authentication before you can
access to those agent. Right? So
remember when you're bidding this always
have security in your mind so that
you're not bidding random things and
that you don't know where is actually
the weakest point in your system. Right?
Make sure you're following the correct
practices and always have that security
concept in your mind. So once you have
so it's going to take a while actually
let's start loading it right you can see
it going to look maybe like five to good
10 minutes right so um you can actually
wait for it to happen right so because
we do this thing allow uh an
authenticated invocation make sure you
are not sure you're not sharing this
particular uh links with any other
people or the internet right because
people can actually come in and talk to
your agent and uh you know they can they
can actually like you know consume your
credits on your behalf right so yeah
Once is everything is running correctly
you should be able to see some links and
then you when you browse to the link
right so when you browse to the link uh
what is going to happen is you're going
to see something like this and then you
can start talking about hi you know
where can I find polar bear and zoo
what's their diet and then what's going
to happen is first whenever user types
something it will actually store the
prompt into like some state and then it
will transfer to the zoo uh the toga
agent right so to agent And okay, I do
not know this information. Find go find
the Wikipedia. From the Wikipedia, get
the animal by species, right? So from
the species, you can say, "Oh, I cannot
tell you where to find a polar bear on a
specific zoo, but I can tell you about
their diet." Then start checking me
about it, right? So if you want to find
a specific, let's say, location, you
might actually want to attach zoo
information, right? Let's say now it's
just Wikipedia. Maybe you own a zoo for
whatever reasons, right? uh then you
have to put in your like opening hours
you know your your your map of like mean
the route that people can use to visit
zoom and stuff. So this is something uh
that you can actually integrate into
your agent and then uh once the agents
have all the information through you
know different pieces maybe uh PDF maybe
images maybe even like a memory that you
actually store in the agent you should
be able to uh accept right you can see
from here uh it's actually using the uh
some clues that we have into figuring
out how many years old from those polar
bear as well right the diet is Mostly
carnivore they eat almost a seals and
different kind of fishes right so if you
are interested in how the flow works you
can kind of see like what's the job
what's the tool uh what's the hands off
happen right uh what's the job of this
comprehensive researcher response for
matter things that I explained already
but if you want to read it you can come
down here and read it as well and if
you're interested to learn more you can
go into ADK docs or you can even
creating like custom tools for your ADK
agent directly over here right So if you
already have enough like okay I'm done
with this right and you can also clean
up your environment. So cleaning up
environment is actually just deleting
the cloud run service that you actually
deployed just now and then you can
delete the repository because we created
the repository before we deploy the
cloud run remember. So once we have
deleted all this thing, you should be
good to go. But in case you're like
paranoid and you're like, okay, I
totally want, you know, don't want to to
to start from maybe like I would say
step three, uh, just delete the entire
thing anyway. So they can delete the
whole project and make sure the project
ID is the ID of the project. So if you
see from here, right, the this is my
name, right? My name is the project name
is AI agent zoo but my project ID is AI
agent zoo486309
right? So if you want to do project ID,
anything that's specific to project ID,
you must add in this number maybe it's
entirely different, right? It might not
actually even be the same as whatever
you are typing over here. So name and
project IDs are different. And make sure
you're typing in a project ID to execute
those task, right? So once you have it,
you will delete it. And remember,
deleting the project is not reversible.
You can't go like, sorry, I delete one
thing. When you delete it, it's gone.
Okay? So make sure you you check
everything before you delete it. And
then yeah that's it the end of the lab
right. So uh there's some recap right?
So we did what we cover for today's
session is I cover a little bit more on
the history of AI agent and why AI
agents are the next frontier and why we
should learn it. At the same time I
cover a little bit more on the
evaluation you know uh evol evolution
which is like from the AI the large
language model with prom to rag to
having tools and just having tools
itself into like multiple tools then
become a agent and multiple agents and
so on. Then we going define into ADK. So
ADK actually help you to assess uh many
different things like uh you know uh
memory you know you have like
orchestration you have like evaluations
and so on. Once you have all these thing
in place then you can start
orchestrating things like you know
sequential agent parallel agent loop
agents and so on. Yeah, all all these
things are being encompassed, right?
Then our lab is focused more on creating
those agent, right? Using the agentic
workflow at the same time deploying to
cloud runs and then you know you have
all the resources that you need to start
updating the agents and then deploy them
on cloud run right make sure to have the
security concept in your mind so that
you don't uh you know get hacked or
something right with that I'm going to
end my session. Thank you so much for
your attention and if you have any
question feel free to reach out and I'm
going to repeat again if you do not
receive any credits uh or any kind of
like ways to access those Google cloud
credits to run those lab reach out to
the team and also check the comments on
uh any of the uh resources that we have
you should also receive an email if you
don't receive an email right just reach
out to the program team and they should
be able to get back to you thank you so
much and enjoy this segment
>> all right so thank you once again Mr.
Toya for a very insightful session and
thank you to everyone for joining us
today and actively participating. We
truly appreciate your time. Uh before we
close, I'd like to quickly walk you
through the next steps which are very
important for your success in this
program.
Firstly and most importantly uh we have
to start with your dashboard. So once
you log in your dashboard is your single
source of truth. This is uh where you'll
find workshop recordings uh your
learning modules, code labs and updates
for each phase of the program. If it's
on the program, it will appear on your
dashboard. The earlier you complete
these, the stronger your foundation will
be. By now, you should have already
received the credits and access details
in your inbox to attend the code lab
that was just delivered by our speaker.
The code lab is a key part of the
program as it helps you apply what you
have learned through guided hands-on
exercises based on real world scenarios.
We strongly encourage you to complete it
now that you have access to reinforce
today's learning. In addition to the uh
core content, specialized deep dive
tracks are also available through Google
skills. Uh this allows you to explore
topics in more depth, strengthen your
expertise and practice beyond the core
curriculum.
You should have already received the
required credits and uh we highly
recommend using this resource to enhance
your learning experience. And then once
like once you have completed the
workshop and the code lab for track one
uh you can uh you can move ahead by uh
attempting the MCQ assessment which is
another important step toward completing
your program journey. uh and after
gaining both theoretical knowledge and
hands-on experience uh you will see that
project submission will be open uh in
your participant dashboard. So you can
submit a track aligned project
individually through the academy
platform and then uh you can start
applying your learning to build a
practical real world application.
uh then participants who complete all
required action items of the cohort
academy in at least one track will
receive a geni master certificate in the
respective track. Uh all successful
participants will also be invited to the
graduation ceremony uh where the top 10
performers will be uh recognized and
their projects will be showcased. So
again, you'll also participate in a
cohort hackathon where you'll work in
teams of two to four to solve a given
problem statement and build innovative
AI solutions. Uh and participants who
complete the cohort academy and the
hackathon and rank among the top 100
performers will be invited to join the
Genai elite club. And this is our
exclusive aluminina network. The
ultimate space for the top developers in
the ecosystem to hang out, collaborate
and stay at the forefront, forefront of
the innovation. If you have any
questions technical or program related,
please reach out via the Discord channel
or through email. And thank you once
again for being part of this journey. We
are excited to uh see your progress and
look forward to connecting with you
again soon. So have a nice day. See you
in the next one. Bye-bye.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Heat
>> Heat up here.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Heat up
here.
[music]
Heat up here.
>> [music]
>> Heat
up here. [music]
[music]
Heat.
Heat up
here. [music]
>> [music]
[music]
>> here.
Heat.
[music]
[music] Heat.
Heat
up here.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Heat.
Heat. [music]