[music]
Da
da da.
>> [music]
>> Hey. Hi. Good morning, good afternoon,
good evening from wherever you're
joining in uh from the APAC region. So
welcome to the introductory session of
Genai Academy AP pack edition. So
building on the successful launch in
India wherein we had a lot of developer
in interests over the past year we are
introducing an expanded APAC edition of
Genai Academy. The Google Cloud Genai
Academy APAC 2026 is a premier
challenge-based learning and development
program designed to significantly
upskill technical professionals
and developers across the region in
generative AI technologies on Google
cloud.
So as I was mentioning right, we were
doing Jane Academy in India the past
year after all the reception that we
received, the amount of encouragement
from the developer ecosystem, the amount
of upskilling, the people, the stories
that we got, how they were upskilling on
Google Cloud Technologies. We are here,
we are inviting the developers from ACI
Pacific region now. So this edition is
open to the entire Asia Pacific region.
The countries that you can see over here
starting from India, Australia,
Indonesia, Philippines, Singapore, uh
Bangladesh, China,
Korea, all the countries and many others
which are in Southeast Asia, Korean
region, Australia, New Zealand, etc. are
welcome to participate in this edition
of Genai Academy.
Okay. So while the question remains for
the developers like what is in it for
them what is the journey that they would
be going through what is in it that they
will be getting out of this program. So
first of all without uh wasting much of
time I'll quickly take you through what
is in it for the developers. So any form
of a developer whether they are
professionals or startups whenever they
register onto this program they are
selected they are made to choose a
track. So there are different tracks if
you'll see right now there's one cohort
the first cohort is live on the website
for those who have already registered
and have joined us today.
So you'll have multiple cohorts. The
first cohort is live at this stage. The
first action in the cohort that you need
to do is select a track. Tracks are for
different functionalities. Uh some might
be AI heavy, some might be data heavy,
some might be infrastructure heavy. Um
once you have selected a track, you
attend your respective workshops for
that track. You get a hands-on learning
from Google developers who would be
taking these sessions. And again, of
course, we'll be having multilingual
sessions. uh so to speak of uh to be
precise we'll be having sessions in
English we'll be having workshops based
on bahasin language for Indonesian
region we'll be having in Korean
language as well as we'll be having in
uh
Chinese language then moving on we the
next step that we have is completion of
code labs so code labs is an essential
part is a mandatory step that needs to
be completed by developers post that uh
you can also opt for completing Google
skills wherein you'll be learning more
enhanced
and completing on hands-on labs of
Google cloud technologies post which
there's an MCQ assessment which is a
checkpoint for the developers who have
completed all these steps and on all of
these learnings that they have had in
their track be the workshop be the
completion of code labs which are
associated with those workshop And then
again the Google skills that are
associated with those workshop and the
MCQ assessment you will be building upon
a project which will be a submission for
this project
post which the hackathon would be open
for that specific cohort. So each cohort
starting from right now as we are
speaking we are in the first cohort of
this entire academy program. uh the
first cohort will have the hackathon
towards the end of the cohort and post
that we again start with a new cohort
with new tracks etc.
Now uh what's in it for developers I
told you the upskilling journey we I
told you what you will get out of it in
terms of learning etc but that's not all
obviously we have a lot of prizes
rewards etc. So there's cash prizes,
there's genai master certificate that
you'll get upon completion of the entire
academy journey. So if you complete the
entire academy journey, you will be
eligible for a genai master certificate.
Obviously there will be goodies in
between which you can claim multiple
campaigns that will be running. Then
there will be a graduation ceremony. So
until the hackathon of the cohort, the
entire phase is the learning phase
wherein you are attending a workshop,
you are completing code labs. If
required, you can also complete certain
Google skills. Then post that you'll be
attending the attempting the MCQ. If you
clear the if you clear the initial
benchmark of the MCQ score, you'll be
also submitting a project. If all the
steps have been completed successfully,
if all the criterias are met, you'll be
getting Chennai master certificate,
you'll be uh having a graduation
ceremony for people who are completing
those. And again, obviously there's
something which is Chennai elite club, a
alumni network which would be created
out of this. So there's a lot to take up
both in terms of learning, both in terms
of rewards, in terms of recognitions.
Now having said that um
what's in it for the top performers cuz
we know there would be lots of
developers thunds of developers would be
participating. So how do we recognize
the top performers?
So for that uh if I deep diver into the
reward section, participants who
complete all the action item in at least
one of the tracks will earn the GI
master certificate. As I mentioned
earlier, all the competitors will be
invited to the graduation ceremony where
we'll also celebrate and showcase the
projects of the top 10 performers. These
top 10 performers would be selected on
the criteria of their MCQ assessment
score plus the projects that they have
built in the academy phase. Finally, the
participants who completed the academy
and the hackathon and rank among the top
100 performers will be invited to join
the exclusive Genai elite club and
illuminate network and we will also have
other exclusive rewards in different
stages for our perform performers in
this entire duration.
So overall this is what the program is
right now. We are talking about cohort
one because that is live at this stage.
And to elaborate further understand what
all nitty-g gritties would be there I'd
like to introduce the speaker for the
today Prasant Subramanyam who is leading
Google cloud developer relations for
JPAC and Google cloud. Hey Prasant how
are you doing?
>> Doing awesome Kos thanks for having me
here.
>> Yeah it's it's great to have you over
here Prasant. So over to you now I'd say
uh the entire audience is yours. We are
having a great crowd today and they are
all eagerly awaiting for what's in it
for them after the great success of Jana
Academy the last year in India and now
we are expanding it to Apac regions. So
over to you Prasad.
>> Awesome. Awesome. Thank you. Thank you
Koshik. Thank you so much for having me
here and u yeah super excited to be here
to uh talk to you all and you know
launch this program. Um so um checking
if my slides are on the screen.
>> Yes, there.
>> Yep, there we go.
>> Okay, awesome. [clears throat]
Um cool. So [sighs and gasps]
like I said, super excited to be here to
launch the first cohort. All right, so
let's let's start with this. This is the
first cohort that we're going to be
running as part of the Gen AI Academy uh
in 2026, right? And uh this is the
cohort that is going to be running from
January till March. So we're going to be
running this quarterly. Um it is
February as you can see while we're
doing this uh session but uh the website
has been live. You would have been
registered and you can maybe already
start looking at some of the content and
how we're going to go through this.
Right? So the cohort has essentially
started and we are taking it a notch
further through February. So the way
that you look at this right as you can
clearly see from on the slide right now
is we have thought about each cohort
structured into two parts or two phases.
The first part is what we like to call
the academy right and this and that uh
the next thing that follows from the
academy is the hackathon. So we are
looking at a very structured way or
approach to learning right. So in the
academy what the participants will do is
you are going to learn you are going to
apply your concepts and um um
it looks like my slides are
disappearing. Uh
Koshik if you could just check if my
slides are okay and if they're
displaying um let me know.
Uh Prashant is uh back now, but we did
see there was a glitch for a duration.
>> Yeah, I think it looks like whenever you
go out of the screen, so why don't you
stay on the screen with me? I'll have
your company there. [laughter]
>> Yeah,
>> no it's it's always fun, right? It's
always exciting when we have to handle
some technical issues while we are
presenting. Uh so
>> uh right, so as I was saying, uh we
looking at this in two phases. One is
the academy phase and one is the
hackathon phase. So in the academy phase
what we're going to be doing is we're
going to have a very structured learning
program. So we're going to be looking at
teaching you certain concepts. We're
going to give you practical real world
examples and real world implementations
to learn and implement these concepts.
Right? So we'll be having um hands-on
code labs. We'll be having sessions u as
well learning content. We'll be walking
you through workshops where you will do
hands-on learn these skills uh by
actually implementing it. We also have
optional uh Google skills labs right and
why this is optional is this is your
learning investment right so these are
uh resources that is available to you to
learn and make use of right but whether
you think the code labs and the sessions
are sufficient or whether you think you
want to go through uh additional
learning content in the form of Google
skills labs that's completely up to you
uh as Koshik was saying we will then
have multiple choice questions so MCQ
assessments and finally uh project
submission where you can showcase your
learning, right? You have to whatever
you learned, you apply that and show
that you are actually able to implement
a project using these skills. Now, this
is the practical part of it, right? Once
that is done, every cohort at the end of
every cohort, we'll have a cohort
specific hackathon. And here, everyone
who is part of this cohort will be given
a single problem statement, right? So,
you'll have a common problem statement
and you will try to solve this
challenge, right? And we we will get to
more details about the logistics of how
this hackathon will happen as we get to
that stage. But you form teams and you
go ahead and um challenge yourself to
solving this problem statement during
this hackathon. So this is how we're
thinking about it, right? Learn,
implement and then challenge yourself,
right? With your learnings.
Um yeah. [gasps]
So in cohort one the way we are thinking
about it is all right we've just we have
kickstarted this off so what we want to
do is you have been using AI you have
been using AI agents you've been
building a lot uh of things yourselves
right um what we want to do is we want
to see how to take you from going beyond
simple demos and prototypes to actually
building production ready jai
applications on Google cloud right so
that is a theme of the first cohort and
we as Koshik mentioned there are
multiple tracks. You can choose which
track you want to be up uh you want to
learn. All right. And we have
essentially three tracks that we have
come up with in cohort one. And each of
it addresses one specific aspect of this
production ready ja applications. Now
you can choose one or more of this as
per your interest as per the time that
you have available. So the first track
is about building and deploying AI
agents. We will be using Gemini. We'll
be using Google's ADK or the agent
development kit and we will be deploying
agents to cloud run. So this is track
number one. All right, building and
deploying AI agents. In track number
two, we will see how you can connect
these AI agents to real world. Right? So
you could it could be tools, it could be
services and uh you know we will be
using the industry standard protocol
that where agents talk to tools, right?
This is called MCP or model context
protocol for those who know of this. Um
and again if this is uh sounds um alien
then you know just wait uh we will have
uh explain this more as we go through
those sessions and workshops that we
have planned for you. So track two is
how you connect your AI agents that you
have built um to real world data. And
then track three, right? You have your
application, you build anything, you're
going to be running it in production.
You of course want to be storing
information. This could be user
information. This could be
personalization, application
information. You need databases and not
just any database databases that is
ready for you. It's this current AI
generation or AI ready databases, right?
So for example, things like an alloy DB.
So we'll be introducing some of these
databases to you and um you know helping
you understand how you can leverage this
while building out your A applications.
So these are the three three tracks and
we'll be also going through the learning
outcomes and how you're going to be
incorporating some of these learnings uh
as you go along.
[gasps]
Awesome. Um so again all right uh double
clicking into the way that we have
structured this um this is a quarter of
learning continuous learning technical
mastery going really deep into some of
these concepts and coming out with um
skills and capabilities that help you be
market ready right and that where you
have projects that you could showcase
your learning so this is how we're
thinking about it and this is as we said
this is cohort one. So we'll be having
this in three cohorts, right? So this
cohort 1, two, and three uh on a
quarterly basis, we'll be having three
cohorts that walk you through this
learning approach. So it's not just a
single training, right? We're not just
going doing one training and then you
know you forget about it. Uh you know,
we don't want to leave you there and you
also don't want that to be the way that
you uh go about, right? Learn something
and then not know what to do with that.
So we are going to form a very rigorous
program of learning challenging yourself
building projects and using our guided
challenge based learning approach that
you're come up with. Um right so this is
this is where you'll be using as I said
the cohort one is going to be about uh
using some of our genera tools using the
SDKs and ADKs thinking about container
runtimes and how to use databases to
solve some of these complex real world
challenges. Okay. So this is this is um
the uh structure that we're thinking
about. Great. Um I think we understand
how the program is going to be run,
right? And you will experience it as we
go along. But let's get started a little
bit in terms of context setting, right?
And um of course you would have heard me
namerop this particular word multiple
times through the last uh I don't know
10 minutes that I was talking and that
is agents, right? So it's important for
us to really understand what agents are.
And as part of this first session, I'm
just going to level set everyone in
terms of again where what are agents,
how we think about agents so that you
can understand again as you select those
tracks where some of these concepts and
skills and technologies come in.
So what are agents? I'll get to what is
there on the slide, but
agents have been a buzzword since maybe
the last year, maybe even before, but
definitely it was a buzz word in the
last year, right? 2025 and we are
continuing in 2026 to use the word
agents and the and agents itself as a
concept continues to ride this hype
cycle. So, which means this is here,
right? This is there's something about
it. It's not uh gone up the hype cycle,
gone down and then people have forgotten
about it. It is still very very
important. We haven't exploited the full
potential of agents and we continue to
build more and more autonomous agents
that solves real world problems and use
cases. So agents is really really
important. There is a lot that we can
still innovate and do with it. But it's
important for us therefore to understand
again what exactly are agents, right? so
that we can leverage it in the best way
possible. So going to the definition
that we have the way we think about
agents you you'll see multiple
definitions of agents but the way we
think about it is agent is essentially
an application right that is that's
that's a baseline it is like any other
software application that you've been
building agent is an application but it
has some specific aspects to it first
aspect it uses AI models the generative
AI models the large language models it
needs to use that because that is the
brain of the agent it needs to use that
in order to make decisions in order to
think about the problem statements and
then agents have the capability to act
independently based on how it is
thinking about the problem right so it
can act independently in order to
achieve a user specified goal. So agents
are again goal oriented and um it is
able to think independently and act
independently to go and achieve the goal
that you have defined for it and it
needs a little bit a bunch of
capabilities in order to be able to do
that right we'll get into those things
but why agents right why is again why
all this hype why all this buzz why do
we keep talking about agents there must
be something to it right it is not just
a software system um and again this is
where I would like everyone as you're
going through these programs s to
internalize this concept of agents and
build out agents the way agents are
meant to be. All right. And why what
what is so different about agents? First
part is very important, right? Agents
are flexible.
This if you compare it to traditional
systems, software systems which are
rules-based, right? You have clear
algorithmic paths. You say if this do
this, else do that, right? So you have
clear algorithmic paths and agents don't
need to follow those algorithmic paths
right in fact it just it shows its
capability when it doesn't reason they
can adapt to users inputs they can
handle edge cases by themselves you
don't need to go and define those edge
cases right again if this happens if the
user provides this then go do this thing
right agents are able to once given a
goal agents are able to figure this out
by themselves and also the great thing
about agents is you don't need to
interact with them in specific format,
specific inputs. It is able to
understand natural language and you can
converse with agents in natural language
be it via text, via via voice or
whatever be it. Um, right. So agents are
really really flexible and
very unique as compared to traditional
software systems. Agents focus on the
outcomes rather than the approach. You
don't tell it how to do things. You tell
the agent what to achieve and that is
the difference
since these agents are built this way
right it's a dynamic it is meant to
think for itself it also makes it very
easy to prototype right
it will figure its way out to the
outcome uh right so there's a lot you
you can you can get agents out there
build agents if you use the right tools
and techniques in a much faster way and
um we have evolved right through 24
through 5 we have evolved our tool
chains, our frameworks in such a way
that it's very easy now to build out
these agents and to test these agents,
right? So it makes it very easy to
prototype and uh start testing and see
how it is working.
Finally, agents are also um have the
capability to be proactive. They can run
based on certain triggers. they can run
based on a schedule and this makes this
intelligence that it has available in
very proactive and helpful ways. Right?
So these are the capabilities and power
that we're seeing of agents and which is
why they're so popular.
While we build these agents again you
know it sounds very fancy but not
everything needs an agent and this is
the first thing that we should be
thinking about as we build out agentic
applications. There are a good number of
cases where agents are a great fit,
right? For example, what we have here is
um you know, maybe you want to create a
system that gives you a personalized
uh learn that you know, you create a
personalized learning agent. Let's call
it that, right? And this is an agent
that adapts to your learning style, to
your individual preferences, the way you
want to learn, the topic that you want
to learn. So, it's not a app
one-sizefits-all app where everyone has
to follow a given learning path. The app
can adapt to your individuality, right?
And that is what makes it an agent,
right? That it can it's highly
personalized, it can adapt, it can be
dynamic. You can have agents for example
that solves business problems using real
time data sources, right? So it uses
real-time signals and real-time
information and based on that signals,
it can adjust itself, can adapt itself
and solve business problems. So here as
well, agents are a great use case. Uh
what about you're building applications
where you want to give a c good customer
experience right u again you the typical
way that you would have seen systems is
rulebased provide this information give
me this screenshot show me something
else right and maybe that is not the um
flow for every individual right so again
when you go into a customer interaction
system your first question is okay what
do you want what is a problem select
this problem uh you know do you have a
damaged package is the item damaged or
is a package package damage. So a lot of
ifels conditions, right? Whereas if you
want to give your customer a great
experience, you can build systems that
are completely autonomous that can use
signals to understand what the user
wants and take them through the right
flow. Right? Uh so again agents are very
good use cases for this. In in a
nutshell, the bottom line is that agents
are outcome focused, right? You have the
outcome that you want to achieve and the
agents help lead you towards that
outcome. Now at the same time there are
cases where you don't need agents right
agents don't make sense or they're
overkill. So for example, if you just
have a large uh you know you want to
generate a document or or generate let's
say uh summarize a document and maybe
you want to uh uh it's it's just a large
prompt that you have right you you have
a lot of text you have a system
instruction you just want to send that
prompt to your large language model and
get back a response right get a response
or make it write write the response into
a document whatever be right input
output in such a case it is just an API
call you don't need an agent in in this
case, right? And again, I'm elaborating
some of these things because you'll be
using this as you build out your
projects, as you go into that hackathon,
right? So, I would like all of you to
think about really agents, how they are
useful, where they can be used, right?
So, in these cases where just prompt
based applications, you don't need an
agent, right? An API call is good
enough. How about you build maybe Q&A
systems, right? where you have knowledge
bases and you want to query those
knowledge bases or you want to return
results based on that knowledge base
based on only that information, right?
The user asks something, you reference
uh some material and you give a response
back to the user. Again, in this case,
maybe you don't need agents, right? Um,
if this is the only thing that you're
thinking about, definitely you don't
need agents. Maybe there is more that
you think about in which case we can
double click more. But typically in
these cases you need a rag architecture
or retrieval augmented generation
systems right um so building chatbots
that can tap into a rag um system is
good enough you don't necessarily need
agents that is goal oriented or uh you
know that can that needs to be
autonomous in these cases
finally if you have systems where you
want predictability right um you have
you're in regulated environments where
you need to explain why a system took a
decision that it took, right? Uh these
are regulated environments. Again, in
these cases, AI or generative AI may not
make the most sense, right? So, in this
case, you stick to your traditional
machine learning models or uh you know,
maybe things like classifiers. Uh you
stick to those, right? And this is what
we call predictive AI. So, you stick to
predictive AI and you don't need to use
generative AI or build these agentic
systems in these kind of cases. So again
think about your use cases think about
what you can do and you can mix and
match this right but it's important that
you leverage these systems for the right
kind of use cases
okay um so we spoke about where it can
be used where it uh doesn't make sense
to be used um and we also spoke about
the kind of hype and why everybody's so
excited about agents right but agents do
also come with their own set of
challenges and um predictability is one
thing we spoke about this as we uh in
you know in the previous slide as he
spoke about those certain environments
and certain systems but it is important
to understand at the end of it your
agentic systems are driven by your large
language models and large language
models are inherently nondeterministic
by nature right you need not get the
same output every time you give it the
exact same input right it could vary and
you have to use a few techniques to
probably try to get some repeatability
but there is no guarantee in that right
so if you need predictability if you
need systems to behave exactly the same
every single time um you know you you
may have some uh it's a it's an
expectation mismatch I'm not saying that
you should or should not expect it but
there's an expectation mismatch if you
expect agents to behave in a predictable
way so that is one of the challenges
that you will be facing
um agents you compared to traditional
software development, the way that we've
been building software systems, agentic
systems are still new, uh I would like
to say they're not yet as stable or as
mature, especially when it comes to
things like error handling. There could
be cases where you know maybe it it goes
into uh um situations that you do not
expect it to, right? So um it could fail
in certain cases. Maybe sometimes the
resilience of these systems are a bit on
the lower side. Um it may not be able to
recover from a specific path. Right?
Because in rulebased framework the the
way that you build these systems, it's
very easy to control the flow, right?
You have your conditional flows, you
have your exceptional flows and you're
able to uh make your systems more
resilient. Whereas building systems and
essentially this is a mindset problem,
right? trying to build agentic systems
the way that we were building
traditional systems is not the right
way. Right? And if you start trying to
think about the um error handling and
repeatability and resilience uh that
this is something where there are some
mismatches and again these are the kind
of challenges that you will face. uh
right um practices like security,
practices like privacy, these are still
evolving areas in the world of agentic
systems, right? So that is something
that you should be aware of.
And finally,
traceability and debugability of these
agentic systems. It is not very easy to
be able to debug
an agentic system specifically
trying to trace what the LLM is doing
and why it is doing it. Right? If you
want to understand how the LLM arrived
at a particular thought process, a
reasoning, it may not be possible to
trace that, right? Or be able to debug
that. Um so you know like I said before
don't treat agentic systems the way that
we would work with a traditional
software system right you'll have to do
it in different ways you'll have to have
checks and balances allow the agentic
system itself to recover and follow the
right path towards the expected outcome
and expected goal so these are some
agentic challenges that you will be
facing and I would like you to keep this
in mind as you go through some of the
learning curriculum that we have
prepared as you go through some of the
practical exercises and try to and how
to handle these kind of situations when
we are building agentic systems.
Okay, so we spoke about a lot about
these systems, right? Agentic systems um
continues to be very important,
continues to be exciting uh space for
all of us. Uh a lot of investment is
going on in this lot of tool chains,
runtimes, tool chains, everything is
being built up, right? Uh what are the
challenges that we face? Uh what are the
benefits of agentic systems? All of this
we have we understand the systems now
but what do you need now to actually
build out these agentic systems the
important thing again is it is a
software system as we said it is an
application and we need to ensure that
we have a reliable architecture for
running these agentic systems right or
for building agentic systems so what are
some of the key things that we need the
first thing is we of course need this
agent has to run somewhere it can't run
on your laptop right it's like you built
a HTML page on your laptop on your
personal machine and said okay everyone
come and use it that's not how it scales
so you need a runtime where you can
deploy and run these agents and cloud
run on Google cloud is a great option
right it's a serverless containerbased
runtime platform and um it works very
well for these agentic systems um
agent of course you you need the brain
you need the model the large jungage
model that powers this whole agent right
so So that is the next thing that you
need and again Gemini 3 which is our
latest state-of-the-art model is
designed specifically for this right
it's designed for agentic workflows it's
designed for taking actions using the
tools that you give it right so choosing
the model right model is very very
important to build out your agentic
system and final bit is you need to give
your agent hands and legs right it needs
to be able to connect to and talk to the
outside world um and this outside world
could be things like databases could be
things like APIs, services, maybe other
systems, maybe document uh
sources. So, you need to be able to plug
in tools into your agent. So, this is
the architecture, right? An agent needs
a runtime, it needs the brain, it needs
a model, which is very very important
and it needs um the ability, it it needs
information, right? So, you connect it
to external systems and this is what we
call as tools. So this is the
architecture of an agentic application.
Okay. Um and again see I don't want to
go through everything because of course
uh we will go through this as part of
those tracks right. So you choose your
tracks be it you know running a
deploying engine applications where we
talk more about the runtime aspects. Uh
the second part which is about using MCP
we will talk there about how to connect
to tools. Third part is databases. is
the third trackers databases where you
will learn about how to um you know um
what are the right kind of places to
store your data how to give your agent
memory even right you don't want your
agent to be stateless or you know uh
ephemeral it if you want to be able to
persist information you need to plug it
into a database so we will talk about
all those aspects but again remember
that this is what forms an agentic
architecture so again uh just to recap
as you do this as you go through this
learning as you go through this cohort
you will learn a lot of uh concepts and
skills. Maybe some of this you already
know and you want to upskill on this.
Maybe some of this is brand new to you.
Leverage this cohort based approach.
Leverage the Google experts that will be
coming in and they'll be delivering
these sessions to you and use this
opportunity to learn. Right. So the
first thing you will learn definitely
about ADK or the agent development kit.
This is an open-source um agent
framework that we have created at Google
and you can very easily build your uh
agents. Um we are supporting multiple
languages, right? But we will take you
through some of the Pythonic uh agents
to start with as we go through this
course and you can use ADK to build your
agents and you can even use it to run
your agents, right? You either use it to
run locally to test for testing purposes
or you can deploy your agents to Google
cloud um using you know the framework
supports this out of the box. So that's
one of the things that you will learn.
You will learn about Google cloud run u
sorry Google cloud run. You will learn
to use it. You will experience Google
cloud run the capabilities of it. It's a
really really powerful environment that
lets you run agents easily and at scale
and irrespective of any language of
framework. Right? So Google Cloud Run
can really help you there. You'll start
by learning to use it with a ADK and
Python but you know you're free to go
explore more capabilities of it. It is
very cost- effective and scalable. All
right, perfectly suited for agentic
applications. In fact, it's also a great
platform to run MCP servers. So if
you're going to be building your own
services, uh creating MCP servers and
you want to deploy them somewhere for
somebody else to use, right? Or for you
to use or for somebody else to use,
Cloud Run is a great great platform for
that. But you will learn about MCP as
well here, right? You will learn about
MCP servers. You will learn about how do
you connect your agents to um tools
using this MCP protocol, right? And how
can you leverage again this MCP protocol
to talk to systems, talk to databases,
right? using MCP toolbox and a few other
uh uh products uh and you know
capabilities that we have. So this is
something that you will learn and
finally getting this agent out into
production right you want to um give
your agents let's say memory for
instance um when you want to persist
your agents you know session sessions I
come back I do something I come back
tomorrow I should be able to continue
off from there so giving your agents
memory being able to have some sort of
observability what exactly is happening
right um or or how is what kind of tools
are being called what kind of services
are being invoked, what kind of
information is being passed between each
part of the agent. So having your
observability and monitoring uh is also
going to be very important and going to
be part of this course. So these are all
the things that you will be learning a
lot more but this is how what we
envision some of the key aspects that
you will learn as you go through the
first cohort.
Okay. Um so Google cloud we believe is a
great place to build run um you know and
deploy and take your agents to
production right we feel that it's a
great home for your agents um there are
a lot of capabilities whether any kind
of model that you want to choose you
want to choose some of our Gemini models
GMA models or other third party models
uh Google cloud gives you access to
those models it gives you a variety of
databases right u be it all or any other
posgress database even cloud SQL um you
can have your document storage you have
large data warehouses any kind of data
requirement that you have that you want
to provide access to your agents you're
able to leverage those capabilities
there's a huge variety of runtimes right
be agent engine specifically designed to
run agents be cloudr run where you can
run agents MCP um servers or any other
APIs or services Right? Or if you want
to take um infrastructure control into
your own hands, you even have the
Kubernetes engine, GKE, Google
Kubernetes Engine that is there on
Google Cloud. Right? So, pick and choose
your flavor the way that you want to do
it. Um you'll be able to monitor and
observe. So, an entire operation suite
is available for you on Google Cloud for
you to run and monitor and observe your
agents that are running in production.
Um right, and again being able to
connect to various services, right? be
your Google Drive services, map
services, Gmail, u all of these
capabilities and connectors are also
available uh on Google cloud right so
it's one single home for you that gives
you a lot of capabilities and options
for you to build deploy and run your
agents um so we hope you'll be able to
leverage this uh to take your agents
from the prototype phase from running
locally to actually make it production
ready to being able to share it with
your family and friends even right show
off what you've built and leverage these
capabilities to make your auns uh
something that you'll be proud to share
and that you can give access to others.
All right. Uh with that the last thing
again just as um to repeat and you know
interestingly um
we spoke a lot about agents. We spoke
about how agents are outcome focused and
the JA Academy we have thought of this
as well uh in an agentic approach.
Right? So this program is also outcome
focused right if you if you want to
compare it to agents and we will take
you through all these concepts
everything that I spoke about it's not
just passive learning right you don't
just sit attend a session and then
forget about it or walk away from it you
will go through guided challenge based
learning right and we like to emphasize
this guided challenge based learning is
the way that this curriculum has been
designed you just won't be sitting
through lectures you'll be actively
engaged you'll be doing hands-on you'll
be completing exercises you'll be
solving assessments and challen
challenges. You will be uh uh
implementing projects and submitting
your projects and finally you will
challenge yourself with the hackathons.
All right? So you'll go through this
entire learn build complete compete and
showcase approach as you're going
through this curriculum. Right? Um so
the objective is learn real world
complex problems so that you can leave
this cohort or you can leave this
academy or this process which with not
just knowledge and we'll ensure that you
have deep theoretical knowledge right
but that's not the only thing you also
have market ready
outcomes right market ready projects and
skills that you can then showcase or you
can immediately apply in your uh
day-to-day uh roles that you're going
through right So this is what it is.
Again uh thank you so much for listening
to me uh for all this time. I hope this
was useful for you and uh you know would
love to take any questions if you have
um be about the program be about any of
the technical things that we spoke about
as we said you'll have a lot of these
experts coming over and taking you
through more sessions but to start with
to understand what we're doing if you
have any questions we would love to take
that and with that Koshik I'll probably
hand it up back to you.
>> Yes sir. Thanks for that insightful
session prashant on agents and it was
insightful for me as well no matter how
much we know it's always less when we
hear someone right uh talking about
something as enthusiastically as he was
speaking. So really enjoyed it. Uh how
agents can have certain challenges.
Really enjoyed that session. Had some
relatability of when we develop certain
agents it goes haywire. So yes it was
very insightful. Thank you for that
Prashant. With that uh I'll quickly pick
up few of the questions which I feel are
technical and post that I'll be taking
up the program related questions. Okay.
So I have something. Yes. Uh
okay. So the first question is in ADK
what all we'll learn and are there any
prerequisites?
>> Okay. Um so ADK is a really powerful
framework. It has a lot of features and
capabilities. All right. Um now um let's
start with prerequisites. I think the
main prerequisite is probably just the
ability to program. All right. And if
you have knowledge of Python that is a
great beginning, right? Because some of
our courses will be Python focused. But
ADK is available in a few other
languages as well, right? So you can
always go ahead and use it in the other
languages. But from a learning and
understanding point of view as we do
these courses, uh, Python would probably
be uh something basic, you know, ability
to read and understand Python will be
something that I would say as a
prerequisite. Um, what you will learn,
we will start simple, right? Right. So
you will learn uh in in the first uh
part right we said about um how do you
build agents. So ADK has this ability to
actually build out your agents. So we'll
walk you through the architecture of ADK
what are the features how to build
agents. We will use uh we will show you
the capability to actually deploy um on
a runtime using ADK. Right? So ADK will
be able to package your applications
into containers and you can deploy that
onto Google cloud uh on cloud run or any
other container runtime. we will look at
uh uh how you can connect to tools how
you can use MCP and tools within ADK
right so that is something else that as
we spoke about that is in track two and
three so we'll we'll show that
capability on ADK as well using agents
um and finally yes ADK is a really
really powerful local uh runtime and
debugging environment right so we'll
show you how to use that how to test
your agents how to observe what what
what is happening when you run your
agents when you interact with this
agents, what kind of queries happen. So
all of that is what we will take you
through uh in the first cohort, right?
And again we can do a lot more than uh
around this as we go into the future
things. We would love your feedback as
well, right? How are you finding these
courses? What more depth do you need?
Right? And we can take that as we go
along in future sessions.
>> Yeah, thanks for that. Uh I have another
question from the chat. Yes. So the
question is which database is preferred
for agentic AI?
Um so this this something that I really
like um right in Google cloud all of our
databases is a ready right so for me the
database that you're using right now is
probably the right database right um all
databases on Google cloud be it uh
document store be it RDBMSS
uh right be data warehouses everything
is has is vector ready embeddings ready
and can really be used for any kind of
AI use cases
But that's said we will take the most
popular uh kind of database. We will use
RDBMSS and we'll use Postgress compliant
databases. So this will be Postgress and
CloudSQL or Alloy DB which is also
Postgress compliant database. So we'll
be using these databases because it's
it's the easiest right everyone majority
of the folks use Postgress compliant
databases. You don't need to learn
anything new or anything different. So
in this cohort in this curriculum we'll
be using alloy DB and cloud SQL uh
Postgress databases for uh our agentic
applications.
>> Got it. Thanks for that Prasant. Uh
another question coming up. Um how much
does the cloud run cost us to run a MCP?
I'd say every developer's first thought
that comes when deploying [laughter] on
something cloud is how much will it
cost? So if you
>> absolutely know uh it's really good to
think about this right now. Uh Cloudr
run is
it's an amazing product that we have at
Google Cloud that you should definitely
leverage and it has a really really
healthy free tier. So a lot of our
products have something called a free
tier where up to X number of calls per
day or per month you will not be
charged. And I don't have the numbers at
the right now handy but you can look at
the uh documentation. I would say
upwards of a thousand calls a day uh if
I'm not mistaken is free right so it it
shouldn't cost you anything to develop
and to test your applications. Now of
course you build an amazing application
and you start you publish it and you
drive traffic towards it then of course
you will go beyond the free tier. I
would love for you to get to that stage.
All right. But in terms of the learning
part of it, you shouldn't have to uh it
shouldn't be costing you anything uh to
to use a cloud run services.
>> Got it. Thanks for that. Uh another
question coming up which is can AI
orchestration be used in areas of work
like cyber security and high-end sales?
>> No, absolutely. Yes. Um so it's
interesting. I mean it's it's probably
not not in the scope for uh this cohort
but great I mean just think about it as
well. um you can do multiple things,
right? So one is you can design your own
AI systems to handle uh cyber security
incidents maybe right um
so so again think of it in a goal based
approach right so what do you need what
is the outcome you want to achieve you
want to identify triage what the problem
was what happened you want to maybe
observe and monitor for security
loopholes if there is a new
vulnerability that is discovered maybe
build out systems to go and monitor and
check your existing systems right so
there are lot of such use cases Um and
you can DIY it, do it yourself and build
out these systems in an agentic way. Uh
we have done some of those things,
right? So it is definitely possible you
can do that or what we also have at
Google cloud is we also have out of the
box agents that can uh that that help
you in this in this world right that
protect your existing systems right so
if you're not into the area of cyber
security and you just want to secure
your systems then you can use some of
our existing agents right which does
some of this you know bot detection and
all these other things uh protecting
your MCP servers even uh from attacks
right so a lot of these readym made out
of the box services so Yes, bottom line,
yes, it can be used. Um, we are not
going to be covering it, but I would
love for you to think about it, right?
Because these are the areas that we
should be thinking about as we build
agentic systems. All right, because
these this is this is real uh problems
or real concerns that we should be
having as we think about agentic
systems. Um, sales even, right? Again, I
know a lot of use cases where people use
this to come up with sales plans,
marketing plans. uh uh we spoke about
how agents can use real data, real world
data and real-time information to adapt
and change how it behaves right so that
it can be used as that as well. I mean I
would say yes but how you would use it
this is where you would need to think
about it apply your domain knowledge and
try to you know implement your agents in
that way. Yeah.
Um under one question it's pretty open
to be honest but uh how to decide on a
model that we want to use for example if
we want to build a project on accounts
related feature then where can I run
some data tests for best alm
>> sure
[sighs]
multiple ways to do it right um way I
would recommend it just start with start
with Gemini right it's it's a very
powerful model. It can do a lot of
things and it is cost effective as well.
Right? You can start with the Gemini 3
flash model, right? The flash model is
very very cost effective. Uh right and
you can really understand if
how to build your systems which is the
first part. So model is one thing right
but are you building out your agentic
systems in the right way? Are you
building out your AI applications in the
right way to solve the right kind of
problems? That is even more important um
than spending all your time trying to
find the right model. So use the model
which has a great price toerformance
ratio. As I said, Gemini 3 flash is one
such model that you can use. All right,
start with that model. Start building
your applications and then do evals.
Right? So you know when you speak about
data tests, you want to run evals. you
want to see how your system is
performing and handling different user
inputs and different uh prompts or
different goals that the user is trying
to achieve. Um you'll have to put some
heristics in, right? So if the user
let's say let's say the user wants to do
something and they're not happy with it,
they may give you a thumbs down, right?
Or they may repeat the question and
these are signals that you will use. So
you will you will run your evals, right?
will have eval sets and then save all
this as eval sets so that you can run
this as you build an iterative system so
that you know you don't have a
regression something that was working
doesn't stop working so you will do all
of these things ADK has this capability
ADK has a capability of again running
evaluations so when you use ADK when you
see the local development UI you will
see there's a tab called evaluation
right so that is something that you can
use to actually test uh keep interacting
with the agent run those evaluations and
see if it is performing the way that you
expected to perform. Once you get your
baseline established, now it makes it
easy to just swap your models, right? If
you don't have your test harness, if you
don't have your framework and your use
cases set up, there is no way you're
going to decide on the model that you
should be using, right? So, like I said,
start with a with a high cost to
performance ratio model. Um, right? Or
low cost, high performance uh model. um
and then build out your systems, observe
what it is happening and if you then
think that you want to change the model
for any specific reason like maybe you
want to fine-tune the model for a
specific use case, you can then do it at
that point of time and then compare
against your evals. Right? So that is
the approach that I would recommend.
>> Got it. Uh just a couple of few more
questions are popping up. I'll just
quickly pass them through. So can we get
exposed to RSFL based tuning the agents
currently? How effective and
userfriendly is it?
>> Sure. Uh Google Cloud has RLHF um
services, right? Uh so Vortex AI has the
ability to uh tune your model um right
uh fine-tune doing RLF tuning. So all
this is possible. It is not part of this
curriculum. Uh at least it's not part of
cohort one. Um we can think about maybe
including some of this um as additional
[clears throat]
material. Oh, by the way, you will have
access to Google cloud u the Google
skills right the Google cloud skills for
learning and there may be some courses
there that you can use to learn it right
so that is one option um we we'll again
share information uh right the team will
share information in terms of how you
can get access to it how you can do some
of the learnings that is available there
so you can definitely do it there uh
again be conscious that you know there
was a question before about cost doing
these kind of RLHF or fine-tuning will
incur more cost right and which is why
we do not want to go into those kind
things and get you to incur those costs.
Learning it from a theoretical point of
view and learning it from uh you know
from code labs and workshops using cloud
skills that is something that you could
definitely do. Uh but again if you if
many of you are interested in this kind
of a thing then we can think about how
we can incorporate that into future
workshops.
>> Sure. Um another one in terms of
security. So from security point of view
if we run agents locally is it keeping
data to itself or will it be tracked
back to Google if we use it cellular?
>> Um
so
what I would encourage you in any case
right any model that you use is take a
look at the terms and conditions and the
clauses of these models. If you use any
of our model from the enterprise model,
right? whatever model Google cloud gives
you access to like the Gemini models um
they will there are very clear clauses
that is there right so where it says
which specific kinds of model where some
of the data may be used which model
where we'll absolutely not use your data
or none of the data will go back into
the model all right um so
there's no clear answer for this again
it depends we have a huge amount of
models right so there are like if you
look at model garden on vertx AI there
are probably 150 plus models and each
model comes with certain terms and
conditions right so what I would
encourage you is maybe just go through
those terms and conditions and see the
clauses of those models both first party
third party models right and see how the
data and privacy will be handled any
kind of usage I would recommend you to
do that um enterprise models or models
that have enterprise clauses we will
never use your data in that right uh but
there could be some other let's say
preview models or free models where The
clauses may be different. I don't have
the exact clauses top of my head for
every single model. But yeah, please
please refer to the terms and conditions
for each of the model and you will know
how the data will or will not be used in
that.
>> Yeah, thanks for that Prashant. Uh just
a few more questions participants will
be taking up rest will be addressing uh
ticker is running below. So you can
reach out to the support email address
that is being flashed on the screen and
your answers will be your questions will
be answered. So uh just before that
Prashant we'll take a few more. I hope
it's fine with you.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. So okay um it's about your uh like
the statement that you are putting up
you mentioned earlier that we cannot use
agents in regulated environment. So do
you mean that life sciences and
healthcare domain by when you are
speaking about regulated environment?
>> No I mean there are a lot of cases
right? There are a lot of regulated
environments and um
there is no
hard line whether you can or cannot use
right. So when we talk about regulated
environments we need to understand what
those regulations are. For example, like
for example, there could be some
environments where we have a regulation
around the data movement, right? Like
very simple, the data has to be within
the region, the country boundaries,
right? Now, when you use build agentic
systems in these cases, ensure that all
the components of the system, the
databases, the AI models, everything is
within the country region. Now, in
Google cloud, we have regions in Bombay,
Delhi, right within India. If you're
building in India for example I I'm
taking this is an APC wide cohort but
I'm just taking India because I'm based
out of India here but there are two
regions in India right and if I leverage
the uh systems that are you know uh
deploy these resources the API the AI
models uh and the databases and every
other resource that goes into the system
if I have it within India I'm complying
with the local regulations right similar
to any other region we have we have it
in multiple regions across APAC right so
that is one when it comes to regulations
there are other regulations where you
know um um [clears throat] again I'm not
an expert in these domains but for
example there could be some u
regulations around let's say healthcare
or in the medical domain where there has
to be a human in the loop right you
cannot give
medical uh recommendations or uh you
know instructions uh without a review by
a doctor for example so that is a
regulation right if you have those kind
of uh again country to country different
regulations exist but now that is also a
regul related environment. All right. So
ensure in those cases you have a human
in the loop. Uh right and not just
directly give your output to your end
users when you build out your agents.
That is one thing. As I said what I was
saying in the previous case was there
are certain domains where explainable AI
is a regulation. You have to be able to
explain what happened why it happened.
Right? In those cases again uh you
provide more instructions or you break
it down. don't you don't make your
agents completely autonomous. So when
you talk about ADK right again the
question before about ADK um we may
cover it but you will definitely find it
on the documentation. ADK also lets you
create agentic workflows. First do this
then then do this then do something else
right based on certain decisions. Now
that is not a fully autonomous system.
It is a workflowbased system that also
leverages some AI capabilities but again
that lets you be a little bit more
compliant because you have a more clear
flow in terms of how your system
executes. It's not just a uh you know an
opaque box. All right. So again this is
basically what I mean right so there's
no
yes or no answer that you can or cannot
use agents but if there are regulated
environments you need to understand the
regulations right and use an appropriate
kind of uh uh design or architecture to
build your systems out.
>> Got it. Thank you Brashant. Thanks for
that. uh I'll quickly take up a few uh
program related questions that are
popping up and rest that we haven't been
unfortunately not been able to answer
we'll answer as soon as you write back
to us and we are also jotting down your
questions if there are some common
questions we'll be putting it up in FAQs
so that you have a prominent answer to
all of those queries so um yes there are
lot of questions as usual that whether
we get to visit Google offices uh there
are multiple programs across different
uh verticals wherein you get those
opportunities but this is an APAwide
virtual program that we are running for
say the entire APAC region so that help
answer those questions um yeah there are
lot of questions regarding credits so
yes to answer both those questions for
both cloud labs as well as Google skills
so for cloud codelabs you do not need
any credits but to deploy it on cloud
run We'll be providing you with some
credits. You'll have an option on the
dashboard where you can request for the
credits and we'll be providing you
credits for deploying it on cloud run.
[snorts] Uh to answer for Google cloud
skill, Google skills basically will
again you can request for credits. We'll
be providing you those credits and you
can learn as much as you can. That's
suggested uh skill labs which will be
provided to you based on the track that
you choose. You can attempt those. So um
I'd say that answers the questions that
were there in terms of uh credits for
both the Google skills as well as code
labs. Um
yeah one question I see which is program
related but uh I'd say if you could
answer that like what is the difficulty
level of JI Academy? Is it suitable for
beginners with little or no background
in AI or machine learning?
Um
so we do expect I I mean um you you
definitely don't need AI or machine
learning right I mean the traditional
way of machine learning um that we've
been you know predictive AI as we like
to call it uh you definitely don't need
that uh capability uh right uh as long
as you are able to write computer
systems write programs uh write code I
think that is good enough right because
and that that is the beauty of AI right
so you really don't need an advanced
mathematics degree or advanced machine
learning skills to be able to leverage
and use AI. So yeah, I think the answer
is no. Uh for your specific question as
I understand what you're asking, you
don't need uh machine learning
knowledge. You can just come in with any
basic application programming skills and
you should be able to leverage uh the
learning that we have here.
>> Got it. Uh the last question Prashant
for you will the curriculum cover the
topics such as agent evaluation, agent
APKI design patterns?
We may touch upon a few of the design
patterns. Um there is a lot right. So we
may not be able to go through
everything. What we'll try to do is
we'll I mean we'll definitely have all
of this as part of the like I said the
optional skills that we have right. So
all of this will be there in Google
cloud skills as optional skills that you
can definitely go through and learn. So
so yes the information will be
accessible to you. The instructor-led
workshops and sessions may not cover
because we cannot do everything of that.
But uh you know leverage the offline
learning capabilities and we'll have
ways that you can even reach out to the
experts you know and uh use the cohort
itself right to to learn and ask these
questions and explore specific aspects.
>> Thank you Prashan. Thanks for that. I
see a lot more queries popping up uh
every moment but uh unfortunately with
the interest of time that we have we'll
be happy to answer all your queries do
not worry the questions that you have
put up if they have not been already
answered we'll be jotting it down we'll
be circulating those if we feel there
are prominent questions across the
participants we'll be putting it in FAQs
and if there are some we'll be
addressing them in the upcoming sessions
that we'll be having as I mentioned
right and just to explain Before we
close the structure is as such we have
three cohorts which will be running
right now. The first cohort is running.
In the first cohort the stages that look
like is that we first complete the
academy part which is the learn more of
a learning based program wherein you
first attend a workshop in which are
multilingual which will be happening in
multi-reional languages. [snorts] Then
you complete a code lab basically the
hands-on lab that was taught to you in
the workshop. you can practice that.
Based on that, you'll also have an
optional step of completing Google
skills based on the track that you have
chosen. Obviously, uh there are again to
uh address that there are three tracks
overall in each cohort. Uh once you have
completed the Google skills as well as
the code labs, you have the opportunity
to attempt the MCQ assessment. Uh there
would be certain parameters for MCQ
assessment passing. Once that is done,
you can then based on your track, you
can submit a make a submission, a
project submission which is your
prototype. Post that the hackathon would
open up for that specific cohort. And
this hackathon I had a few more
questions which I saw that is is team
formation a mandate. So team formation
the team range is from one to four. So
you as an individual can also
participate in those hackathons and
based on that there are rewards and
recognition. There's GNI master
certification. Then there's uh the GNI
elite clubs. All the criterias, how to
proceed, what are the next steps are all
listed on the website. You can have a
view of it. Once you register, you'll
land onto the dashboard wherein you
again will go through a guided step of
what needs to be done. Right? We know
there are a lot of action points, but
it's all for the participants. It's all
for the developers that are out there
who are learning, who are growing. and
then obviously you get to get the
rewards. So with that um I hope we were
able to answer all your queries and once
again Prasan thank you for joining in
and taking us through that insightful
session of what agents are what we can
build with agents and what are the
capabilities as well as what are the
things that we should look into or keep
into mind when we are building agents.
So thank you Prasan. Thanks a lot for
joining in and I hope we have a great
success this time. Again the
participants are more excited and since
we have opened it up for across the AP
pack. So welcome everyone to the Jennai
Academy AP pack edition.
>> Thanks. Thanks everyone for joining.
>> Thank you. Thanks Prasan. Yeah.